Elliott Kvamme

775 Taft Loop S, Cambridge, MN 55008

PH: (763) 377-0163; E: Elliott.kvamme@gmail.com;

GitHub: https://github.com/Bycicleace; Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/elliottkvamme/

Summary

Works well with a team of developers and works well independently. Acquired a bachelor's degree in Computer Science with a focus in Software Engineering. Currently attending and thriving in a Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp through the University of Minnesota. As of November 12th, 2021, am halfway through and have aced all assignments. Has been a Software Developer for 3 years. Has written and implemented the main development procedures, and Git procedures for the current development team. Has led the team through multiple managers.

Skills

- Superior communication skills
- HTML, CSS, Javascript, NodeJS, Express, SQL
- Python, Powershell, Visual Basic
- OpCon Administrator
- Outstanding team player
- Works well in high stress situations
- Strong analytical skills

- Creating Documentation and establishing procedures
- Phenomenal customer service skills
- Exceptional at following detailed instructions
- Works well independently and in a team environment

Education

University of Phoenix

Bachelor of Computer Science

Anoka-Ramsey Community College

Associate of Arts

Cambridge-Isanti High School

High School Diploma

October 2016 Phoenix, Arizona

September 2010

Cambridge, Minnesota

June 2009

Cambridge, Minnesota

Experience

TruStone Financial Federal Credit Union

Dec 2017 – Current Plymouth, Minnesota

Software Developer

Works well with a small team of developers and works well independently. Creates custom reports in a proprietary programming language. Creates connections to various APIs. Wrote procedures for the development team to follow including commenting standards, and file naming conventions. Also wrote Git procedures and set up repositories to maintain. Also currently uses the Scrum Agile methodology for organizing work. Has demonstrated leadership and has helped carry the team through multiple managers.

Cross Pointe Church

Jan 2018 – Nov 2021 Cambridge, Minnesota

IT Administrator

Oversees all technology at the church. In charge network administration, infrastructure design and deployment, security and implementation, and operations. Also manages a budget and makes decisions to purchase new equipment. Prepares for events like the yearly biblical counseling conference. Delegates tasks to volunteers.

TruStone Financial Federal Credit Union

Aug 2016 – Dec 2017 Plymouth, Minnesota

Desktop Support Analyst

Worked with a team of Analysts. Responsibilities include answering phone calls and completing tickets, setting up and removing user access, Setting up and taking down workstations, replacing and troubleshooting peripherals, organization, and completing projects.

TruStone Financial Federal Credit Union

Dec 2014 – Aug 2016 Golden Valley, Minnesota

Lead Teller

Worked 8 months as a teller. Responsibilities include processing transactions, account maintenance, and document organization. Worked 1 year as a lead teller. Projected a positive attitude in a fast-paced work environment. Worked closely with management to achieve goals on the teller line. Responsibilities include all previous responsibilities as well as document retention, storage, and destruction, scheduling, routine and surprise auditing, organization, and training.

Minnco Credit Union

Oct 2013 – Nov 2014 Cambridge, Minnesota

Teller/Member Service Representative

General office work, security, and member service. Responsibilities included transactions, receiving payments, opening and closing accounts, general account maintenance, Balancing and auditing, taking and completing orders.

The Corner Cup

Oct 2012 – Feb 2014 Cambridge, Minnesota

Assistant Manager/Shift Manager

Worked closely with the manager to make general business decisions and financial decisions. Doubled as a shift manager. Designed and implemented inventory tracking system. Other duties included taking and completing custom orders, balancing and auditing, along with general security. Also did some marketing.

Cub Foods

Nov 2007 – Feb 2013 Cambridge, Minnesota

Cashier/Stocker

Worked 3 years as a stocker. Responsibilities included carrying out detailed instructions, organization, and the operation of pallet jacks. Worked 1 year at the Customer Service Desk. Responsibilities include running 2 counters simultaneously and working with multi-line telephones. Worked 1 year as a Customer Service Manager. Responsibilities include customer flow management, interruption management, scheduling, adaptability and auditing.